<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<article lang="en">
<articleinfo>
    <date>2017-10-12</date>
</articleinfo>
<simpara>v0.4.0, released March 31, 2010.</simpara>
<simpara>Cloudera Desktop 0.4.0 is a significant update from the previous version 0.3.0.
This release introduces the Cloudera Desktop SDK, a way to plug in your own
applications that leverage the Cloudera Desktop environment.  Another new
feature is Beeswax, a front-end application for interacting with Hive.  It also
represents many bug fixes and a re-working of the "Job Browser" and "File
Browser" applications.</simpara>
<simpara>NEW FEATURES</simpara>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Beeswax, a UI for Hive
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Beeswax is an application for managing and using Hive.  It allows users
to create tables, load data, and query the warehouse, all from their
browser.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
The Cloudera Desktop SDK
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">It is now possible to add your own applications into Cloudera Desktop,
integrated with the windowing system and the other applications.
To get started, see the SDK documentation.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
File Editor
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">It is now possible to edit (small, text) files directly from the File Browser.
This is particularly handy for editing small configuration files.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
"About" Application
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Reachable by clicking the Cloudera "feather" in the upper lefthand corner,
the about application displays the current configuration.</literallayout>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<simpara>IMPROVEMENTS</simpara>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>
File Browser
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">The File Browser has been re-architected on top of the SDK.
Changing permissions and changing file ownership is now possible.
Performance on large directories is improved.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Job Browser
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">The Job Browser has been re-architected on top of the SDK.
There have been several performance improvements in handling
large jobs.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Job Designer
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">You may register for e-mail notifications when jobs you
submit have completed.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Session Restore
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Windows that were open when you last logged out are
opened again automatically when you log back in.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Support for privileged ports and SSL.
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">You can now run Desktop on port 80, and, optionally, with SSL (see the FAQ).</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Cleaner SDK Model for "JFrame"
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Most requests within Cloudera Desktop are now, under the covers,
simple GET and POST requests which return HTML.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
SDK-Friendly Build System
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">The build system has been adapted to support third-party applications
and dependencies gracefully.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Users can now change their own passwords.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Keyboard Shortcuts
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">A list of available shortcuts is available in the top right corner (click the
"command" icon).</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Usage without Hadoop
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Cloudera Desktop will run if Hadoop is unavailable, though
some applications will be limited in functionality.</literallayout>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Frontend Javascript Performance and Compatibility
</simpara>
<literallayout class="monospaced">Many improvements in windowing performance.</literallayout>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<simpara>KEY BUG FIXES</simpara>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Creating a "home directory" while creating the user in the user manager
  no longer produces an error.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Dates and times are now displayed in a specific timezone, which is configurable.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Inactive users are not able to login.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
The Job Designer appropriately configures hadoop.tmp.dir; this fixes
  some permissions denied errors.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
File upload is more robust.
</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<simpara>KNOWN BUGS</simpara>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>
After a successful upload with Linux&#8217;s flash player (which may warn you about
  hanging your computer), the upload screen does not clear.  Click the red
  (x) button to clear it.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Configuring the web server to listen on port 80 does not work if you are
  using the RPM or Debian packages. This is due to the init scripts
  improperly dropping root privileges before calling the supervisor. This
  has been fixed in release 0.4.1.
</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</article>
